Giovani Velasquez

Junior Full Stack Developer

I am a well-qualified self-taught Junior Full Stack Web Developer with more than two years developing real world projects from the front-end and back-end side. Proficient expectations in most used programming languages as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL to develop and/or integrate new features to run business operations. In order to speed up results, I use React library as my client side and Laravel Framework as my server side.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Digital Investments, Guatemala, Guatemala City. Junior Full Stack Developer

08/2020 - 2021

- Collaborated with the team to identify and resolve software issues, gaining valuable experience in debugging techniques.
- Learned and applied new technologies and techniques, including Git version control and REST API development.
- Assisted in the development of PHP and MySQL web applications, gaining valuable experience in web development.
- Translated designs from Photoshop to HTML and CSS while ensuring that the UX and UI design are maintained

Hivolts Electrical Inc, Brooklyn NY, United States

Licensed and insured electrical company

Humar Resources Specialist

04/2021 - Present

- Specialist to recruit, screen, and interview job applicants and place newly hired workers in jobs.
- Handle compensation and benefits, training, and employee relations.

FREELACE PROJECTS

Real Estate Admin Application

 Real Estate admin application to track customers payments, building expenses and monthly report.

PORTFLIO

https://jsgiovaniwebsites-portfolio.netlify.app/

CONTACT

- 1290 Ocean Ave, Brooklyn, NY.
- +1 917-615-6927
- jsjosgiovani@gmail.com

SKILLS

Front End Development:

- HTML5
- CSS3
- Sass
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Tailwind

Back End Development:

- PHP
- MySQL
- RESTful APIs implementation

Web Services:

- REST/JSON
- Axios
- · Web RESTful API consuming
- Postman

Key Skills:

- MVC Design Patterns
- OOP Paradigm
- Auth Token implementation

Version Control:

• Git/GitHub

Frameworks:

- React
- Tailwind
- Laravel

Languages:

- English
- Spanish

EDUCATION

Del Valle University Computer Science and Information Technology. 10/2013 - 06/2017

OTHER

 Udemy Certificate: Full Stack Web Developer with HTML5, CSS3, JS, AJAX PHP y MySQL.